<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>To Entertain God</title>
    <link>https://toentertaingod.com/</link>
    <description>To Entertain God</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://toentertaingod.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perils of Limiting Freedom of Speach</title>
      <link>https://toentertaingod.com/posts/the-perils-of-limiting-freedom-of-speach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toentertaingod.com/posts/the-perils-of-limiting-freedom-of-speach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://toentertaingod.com/img/pericles_funeral.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Pericles&#39; Funeral Oration (detail), 1853, Philipp von Foltz.&#34; title=&#34;Pericles&#39; Funeral Oration (detail), 1853, Philipp von Foltz.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was speaking at a virtual meeting on the 6th of Jan 2020 when I noticed the attendees&#39; attention wandering quickly. I could see their faces light up with a white flash as they opened their browsers and tuned into their preferred news websites. Concerned by the looks on their faces, I stopped talking. My silence went unoticed. I opened The New York Times and, like them, was shocked by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/09/us/politics/capitol-riot-charges.html&#34;&gt;what happened at the Capitol building that day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President of The United States of America had instigated a violent siege to the Capitol building that killed 5, including a police officer. The assaulters had been encouraged by the POTUS himself on his (now defunct) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump&#34;&gt;Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;. Both Twitter and Facebook decided to ban Donald Trump from their sites. We then learned that Apple had decided to ban &lt;a href=&#34;https://parler.com/&#34;&gt;Parler&lt;/a&gt; (an aspiring social media site that wanted to cash in on the ban) from their App Store since banned government officials turned to it to spread lies. Google soon followed suit and banned Parler from the Google Play Store too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people have praised the tech giants&#39; moves. In contrast, others have cautioned against what we&amp;rsquo;ve really seen: corporations exhibiting more veto power than ever seen before. They left the most powerful man on earth without his main source of influence in a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate about Freedom of Speech is not new at all. Usually, the angle has been that Freedom of Speech has too much potential to offend and harm people, so we should limit it. While there&amp;rsquo;s truth to that, I think the most important point has nothing to do with us needing protection. Of course, taking away a common space where we can all converse doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix the problem at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radicals will still be there. But now they will collude in secret. We won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see what they think, why they think it, or what they&amp;rsquo;ll do in consequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine we didn&amp;rsquo;t ban ISIS accounts. You&amp;rsquo;d be likely to notice that your neighbor&amp;rsquo;s son, for example, has liked a post on Facebook that might not directly be tied to ISIS but sympathizes with some of their radical discourse. It&amp;rsquo;s not common nowadays because the channels for ISIS to captivate and radicalize young minds are underground and not mainstream. The fact is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreign_fighters_in_the_Syrian_and_Iraqi_Civil_Wars#Western_countries&#34;&gt;thousands of young men and women born in the EU have joined the ranks of the terrorist organization&lt;/a&gt;. This is what might happen to alt-right groups from now on: they&amp;rsquo;ll consume &amp;ldquo;bottled&amp;rdquo; mediums where only adepts to the same ideologies will post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that instead of removing these radicals, we&amp;rsquo;re effectively radicalizing them more by forcing them onto untapped, uncontrolled, echo-chamber alternative channels that will increase their anger and sense of repression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad the POTUS can&amp;rsquo;t coordinate a new assault on the Capitol building using Twitter or Facebook. Still, I worry we&amp;rsquo;ve created the necessity for new underground channels that will be far more effective and harder to control. Isolation, after all, is a key part of radicalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getty.edu/visit/cal/events/ev_1210.html&#34;&gt;How Does Democracy Survive Demagoguery?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pjp-eu.coe.int/en/web/youth-partnership/extremism-and-radicalisation-leading-to-violence&#34;&gt;Extremism and radicalisation leading to violence.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Still in the Information Era</title>
      <link>https://toentertaingod.com/posts/we-are-still-in-the-information-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toentertaingod.com/posts/we-are-still-in-the-information-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computers are everywhere. In your pocket, in your TV and even in your fridge. All these devices come with some sort of operating system, enabling developers to write apps for them. One would be inclined to think that this surely is the “Era of computers” or even the “Era of apps”, but I beg to differ. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only reason we came up with computers is to deal with information. If we found something better, computers would go out of fashion instantly. It’s all about transforming data. So, rather than in the “Computer era”, we’re still in the “Information era”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some degree, I’d argue we’ve always been in it. At least every time a civilisation has realised that gathering information for further analysis is valuable. It really doesn’t matter what tools they used to perform that analysis. You probably never heard about the “Abacus era”, so why should we talk about the “Computer era”? Eras are not defined by tools, but by the resources those tools exploit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://toentertaingod.com/img/abacus.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Ancient Greeks using an abacus&#34; title=&#34;Ancient Greeks using an abacus&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps are the tools of our era. We’ve focused on making them easy to write and usable. That’s great, but it’s not enough. We often loose sight of what’s truly important. Yes, it’s nice to have objects so we can model problems easily, or interpreted languages that are programmer friendly and forgiving, but the truth is that these paradigms distract us from our real goal as programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re tool builders –not strictly problem modellers– and we’re in the information business. We should always understand the information we handle and how to transform it in a useful way. Everything else is secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
