<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on To Entertain God</title>
    <link>https://www.toentertaingod.com/posts/</link>
    <description>To Entertain God (Posts)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:24:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://www.toentertaingod.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What Europe Needs to Understand About American Diversity Policies</title>
      <link>https://www.toentertaingod.com/posts/what-europe-needs-to-understand-about-american-diversity-policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:24:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.toentertaingod.com/posts/what-europe-needs-to-understand-about-american-diversity-policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5 id=&#34;disclaimer-im-a-white-man-from-spain-and-the-child-of-two-argentinian-parents-that-makes-me-hispanic-and-latino-i-was-brought-up-in-spanish-culture-and-havent-suffered-a-day-of-discrimination-in-my-life-i-consider-myself-very-fortunate-and-privileged-i-dont-think-anyone-who-feels-otherwise-would-get-anything-out-of-reading-this-piece-so-feel-free-to-skip-to-the-other-ones&#34;&gt;DISCLAIMER: I&amp;rsquo;m a white man from Spain and the child of two Argentinian parents. That makes me Hispanic and Latino. I was brought up in Spanish culture and haven&amp;rsquo;t suffered a day of discrimination in my life. I consider myself very fortunate and privileged. I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone who feels otherwise would get anything out of reading this piece, so feel free to skip to the other ones.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;disclaimer-2-im-writing-in-english-today-because-i-suspect-this-applies-to-other-european-countries-and-not-only-spain-i-might-be-wrong-though&#34;&gt;DISCLAIMER 2: I&amp;rsquo;m writing in English today because I suspect this applies to other European countries and not only Spain. I might be wrong, though.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I live in New York. We planned on celebrating our wedding in Spain (our homeland) on the 20th of March 2020. We flew out there with bags packed for a two-week-long trip and a honeymoon. Coronavirus had other plans for us. We ended up canceling the wedding and were stranded in a locked-down Spain for five months until we could finally make it back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this time, I had a lot of time to watch the news in Spain. I started noticing a trend. Out of 10 new stories in the 24 hours live Spanish TV, four were about how badly the US dealt with the pandemic and racial tensions. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I understand there&amp;rsquo;s plenty to complain about when looking at the USA&amp;rsquo;s pandemic reaction and racial violence, but something felt off. Spain is one of the worst-hit countries in the world when looking at per-population numbers. The public cried for the media not to show bodies piling up in Spanish hospitals. Yet, somehow, everyone felt comfortable commenting on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npr.org/sections/coronavirus-live-updates/2020/04/10/831875297/burials-on-new-york-island-are-not-new-but-are-increasing-during-pandemic&#34;&gt;images from New York&amp;rsquo;s unclaimed body mass-burial in Ellie&amp;rsquo;s Island&lt;/a&gt;. What the hell is going on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve long suspected there&amp;rsquo;s an ill-fascination with the US among Spaniards (and to some extent Europeans). It&amp;rsquo;s like deep-down, we Europeans feel self-conscious about our democracies and liberties and somehow need to declare America&amp;rsquo;s outdated or primitive to feel better about ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t care about this. And from what I gather, the USA doesn&amp;rsquo;t care about it either. But, there&amp;rsquo;s one area of this whole toxic culture that I think we should address: mocking US diversity policies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.toentertaingod.com/img/power_minorities.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Martin Luther King Jr, Barack Obama, and Kamala Harris in a collage&#34; title=&#34;Examples of minorities in power positions in the United States&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no shortage of Spaniards (and generally Europeans) that often laugh at the USA&amp;rsquo;s diversity policies. The mocking is that race surveys and political correctness are just for-show measures to make white Americans feel good about themselves. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe this is the case, but I&amp;rsquo;m not here to argue about that. I&amp;rsquo;m just hoping to make some fellow Europeans reading this reconsider their position on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Someone sent me an article from a prominent Spanish news outlet the other day, which finally prompted me to write this piece. A &lt;em&gt;white man&lt;/em&gt; from Spain complains &lt;em&gt;he&lt;/em&gt; felt discriminated against working in the USA when he had to fill in his race profile in a standard survey. Now, honestly, I don&amp;rsquo;t even know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get the irony out of the way. A white man from a country with less than a 2.5% black population unilaterally declares that a country with a 15% black population is handling diversity all wrong because he misunderstood the purpose of diversity surveys. And that&amp;rsquo;s news worthy for a major news outlet. I&amp;rsquo;d forgive you for thinking Spaniards (and generally Europeans) are self-centered and don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about the rest of the world, which, ironically, is precisely what Spaniards and Europeans think about the USA!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what&amp;rsquo;s going on? Arrogance, in short. Yet another trait that Spaniards and Europeans love to pin on Americans. You see, you can&amp;rsquo;t assume you know a problem when you haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced it first-hand (or even second-hand in the case of Spain). Growing up in Madrid (Spain&amp;rsquo;s capital city), I interacted with a total of three black kids, and I never saw a black man or woman in a position of power. Some Spaniards reading this might be rushing to Wikipedia to find some exception to the rule, but that proves nothing. Exceptions don&amp;rsquo;t make a rule. If we compare New York&amp;rsquo;s diversity during the same period (which isn&amp;rsquo;t even the US&amp;rsquo;s capital), we see a much different story. Less than 45% of New York City is white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For someone to say they&amp;rsquo;re not racist and to mock other countries trying to combat racism is the most arrogant and ignorant position you could ever adopt. Especially for someone who&amp;rsquo;s grown up and worked in an all-white environment in an almost all-white country such as Spain. As much as it shames me to admit this, in Spain, we&amp;rsquo;re in the &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;m racist, problem solved!&amp;rdquo; phase of racism. We know so little about the rest of the world, and we think so much about our own culture that we don&amp;rsquo;t understand our ignorance. What makes me worry even more is that self-appointed progressives seem to be the prime holders of this United States grudge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been criticizing Spain hard for a few paragraphs now, let me try to set the record straight. Spaniards are some of the most understanding and nonjudgemental people I&amp;rsquo;ve met (account for my obvious bias). For example, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gay-friendly&#34;&gt;we consistently rank in the top 10 most LGTB friendly countries globally&lt;/a&gt;. In my experience, 99% of Spaniard&amp;rsquo;s questions about your origin are good-spirited, and just a segway so you can talk about your countries traditions and customs (something we value very highly). I&amp;rsquo;ve also witnessed this country strike down old prejudices and come together to accept change. In other words, I take absolutely no issue with being a Spaniard. Like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/1868-i-love-america-more-than-any-other-country-in-the&#34;&gt;James Baldwin put it&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I love America more than any other country in the world and, precisely for this reason, I insist on the right to criticize her perpetually.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s something similar for me regarding Spain and this piece.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.toentertaingod.com/img/james_baldwin.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;A picture of American novelist James Baldwin&#34; title=&#34;American novelist James Baldwin.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not here to shame my fellow Europeans or try to come across as a racism expert. I could never be that. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been on the receiving end of the pain and oppression racism creates. I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to tell my people from Spain: let&amp;rsquo;s understand we&amp;rsquo;re ignorant about racism and re-evaluate our assumptions as our country becomes racially diverse. Until then, let us quiet down so we might give voice to those we silence by our mocking and loud uninformed opinions on racial issues. After this, I&amp;rsquo;ll be the first one to follow my advice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Perils of Limiting Freedom of Speach</title>
      <link>https://www.toentertaingod.com/posts/the-perils-of-limiting-freedom-of-speach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.toentertaingod.com/posts/the-perils-of-limiting-freedom-of-speach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.toentertaingod.com/img/pericles_funeral.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Pericles&#39; Funeral Oration (detail), 1853, Philipp von Foltz.&#34; title=&#34;Pericles&#39; Funeral Oration (detail), 1853, Philipp von Foltz.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was speaking at a virtual meeting on the 6th of Jan 2020 when I noticed the attendees&#39; attention wandering quickly. I could see their faces light up with a white flash as they opened their browsers and tuned into their preferred news websites. Concerned by the looks on their faces, I stopped talking. My silence went unnoticed. I opened The New York Times and, like them, was shocked by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/09/us/politics/capitol-riot-charges.html&#34;&gt;what happened at the Capitol building that day&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President of The United States of America had instigated a violent siege to the Capitol building that killed 5, including a police officer. The assaulters had been encouraged by the POTUS himself on his (now defunct) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump&#34;&gt;Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;. Both Twitter and Facebook decided to ban Donald Trump from their sites. We then learned that Apple had decided to ban &lt;a href=&#34;https://parler.com/&#34;&gt;Parler&lt;/a&gt; (an aspiring social media site that wanted to cash in on the ban) from their App Store since banned government officials turned to it to spread lies. Google soon followed suit and banned Parler from the Google Play Store too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people have praised the tech giants&#39; moves. In contrast, others have cautioned against what we&amp;rsquo;ve really seen: corporations exhibiting more veto power than ever seen before. They left the most powerful man on earth without his main source of influence in a couple of hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The debate about Freedom of Speech is not new at all. Usually, the angle has been that Freedom of Speech has too much potential to offend and harm people, so we should limit it. While there&amp;rsquo;s truth to that, I think the most important point has nothing to do with us needing protection. Of course, taking away a common space where we can all converse doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix the problem at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radicals will still be there. But now they will collude in secret. We won&amp;rsquo;t be able to see what they think, why they think it, or what they&amp;rsquo;ll do in consequence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine we didn&amp;rsquo;t ban ISIS accounts. You&amp;rsquo;d be likely to notice that your neighbor&amp;rsquo;s son, for example, has liked a post on Facebook that might not directly be tied to ISIS but sympathizes with some of their radical discourse. It&amp;rsquo;s not common nowadays because the channels for ISIS to captivate and radicalize young minds are underground and not mainstream. The fact is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foreign_fighters_in_the_Syrian_and_Iraqi_Civil_Wars#Western_countries&#34;&gt;thousands of young men and women born in the EU have joined the ranks of the terrorist organization&lt;/a&gt;. This is what might happen to alt-right groups from now on: they&amp;rsquo;ll consume &amp;ldquo;bottled&amp;rdquo; mediums where only adepts to the same ideologies will post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that instead of removing these radicals, we&amp;rsquo;re effectively radicalizing them more by forcing them onto untapped, uncontrolled, echo-chamber alternative channels that will increase their anger and sense of repression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad the POTUS can&amp;rsquo;t coordinate a new assault on the Capitol building using Twitter or Facebook. Still, I worry we&amp;rsquo;ve created the necessity for new underground channels that will be far more effective and harder to control. Isolation, after all, is a key part of radicalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getty.edu/visit/cal/events/ev_1210.html&#34;&gt;How Does Democracy Survive Demagoguery?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pjp-eu.coe.int/en/web/youth-partnership/extremism-and-radicalisation-leading-to-violence&#34;&gt;Extremism and radicalisation leading to violence.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We&#39;re Still in the Information Era</title>
      <link>https://www.toentertaingod.com/posts/we-are-still-in-the-information-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.toentertaingod.com/posts/we-are-still-in-the-information-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Computers are everywhere. In your pocket, in your TV and even in your fridge. All these devices come with some sort of operating system, enabling developers to write apps for them. One would be inclined to think that this surely is the “Era of computers” or even the “Era of apps”, but I beg to differ. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only reason we came up with computers is to deal with information. If we found something better, computers would go out of fashion instantly. It’s all about transforming data. So, rather than in the “Computer era”, we’re still in the “Information era”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some degree, I’d argue we’ve always been in it. At least every time a civilisation has realised that gathering information for further analysis is valuable. It really doesn’t matter what tools they used to perform that analysis. You probably never heard about the “Abacus era”, so why should we talk about the “Computer era”? Eras are not defined by tools, but by the resources those tools exploit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.toentertaingod.com/img/abacus.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Ancient Greeks using an abacus&#34; title=&#34;Ancient Greeks using an abacus&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps are the tools of our era. We’ve focused on making them easy to write and usable. That’s great, but it’s not enough. We often loose sight of what’s truly important. Yes, it’s nice to have objects so we can model problems easily, or interpreted languages that are programmer friendly and forgiving, but the truth is that these paradigms distract us from our real goal as programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re tool builders –not strictly problem modellers– and we’re in the information business. We should always understand the information we handle and how to transform it in a useful way. Everything else is secondary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
